[Music]
uh hello and welcome to this business
Cal lunch event session on the customer
manage encryption key and logbox
settings um these settings help you
secure your environments if you have
very Advanced uh security and privacy
needs for your uh environment database
and I'll show you how to do it so first
of all these settings are administered
in the Power Platform admin Center and
for them to apply to your business
center environment you have to link your
business sensor environment to a Power
Platform environment to link your
Platform environment you navigate to the
environment Details page in the business
Central admin Center and there you can
use this setting here to link your
environment to any pek environment Sor
and there you can use this setting here
to link your business Cent for
environment to any Power Platform
environment that's in the same region in
this case the US and of the same type in
this case production after you've linked
your environment you'd be able to see
the details of your LinkedIn environment
in the admin Center as well as the
settings that are inherited from Power
Platform onto your business center
environment in this case that would be
customer managed encryption key and
lockbox um firstly the customer managed
encryption key this is a setting that
administrators can use to encrypt their
business Central Empower platform
environment databases with their own key
managed in our own key Vault rather than
a key that lives in a Microsoft key
Vault um to set this up first of all you
have to link your business censor
environment to a Power Platform
environment if customer managed
encryption key is already enabled on
that Power Platform environment it will
automatically be inherited on your
business Cent for environment if you
have not yet enabled this on your Power
Platform environment uh you have to go
through some setup steps to do
that so to do that you first navigate to
the Azure portal create the key Vault
and make sure that this key Vault has
enabled soft the lead and Purge
protection this is to protect your key
Vault against accidental deletion and
your customer data in your business
Central and Power Platform environment
databases being encrypted permanently
after you create a key Vault you create
a key of type RSA with key size 20 48 um
and this is the key that will be used to
encrypt your database after you create
the key you need to create an Enterprise
policy resource which is act as the
bridge between your key and your uh
environment
databases this Enterprise policy must be
in the same region as your Power
Platform and Business Center
environments so in the example earlier
I had an environment that lived in the
US I should also create this Enterprise
policy in the US for cmk to work after
you've created this Enterprise policy
you need to give it permissions to your
key Vault so you give it the key Vault
crypto service encryption user raw
assignment um and this will enable it to
read the key so that it can then be used
to encrypt your database after that you
make an environment administrator this
is someone with a ENT role that allows
for administration of Power Platform
environments the reader role on the
Enterprise policy so that they can then
go on into the Power Platform admin
Center to apply that Enterprise policy
to the selected environment that is
linked to your business Central
environment after completing this last
setup step there could be some downtime
on your business center and Power
Platform environments yourit the
encryption key that is used to encrypt
your data gets re-encrypted with your
own
key there's a few things that are good
to know as you said this up um the
linked Power Platform managed
environment is required so there's no
way to set this up for business Central
environment without linking your Power
Platform environment and if you unlink
your environments the business Central
environment will revert back to a
Microsoft manage encryption key so the
link must be there to set it up and it
must remain in place for that
environment to be encrypted with your
own key to set this up in the Power
Platform admin centor there are also
specific licensing requirements in
Microsoft 365 and Power Platform and
these will apply to your business
Central environments as
well um as you set this up there's a
risk of internal malicious actors if a
single administrator has access to all
aspects of setting up um the customer
managed encryption key therefore we
recommend that you separate these duties
between different persons in short
there'd be one administrator that
completes the setup steps in the Azure
portal and another administrator that
completes the setup steps in the
business Central and Power Platform
admin centers finally we have some
operations on your business Central
environment that would create a new
environment such as copy and restore
and we support the exporting of
environment databases for these
operations if you copy and restore and
create a new business Cent for
environment the new environment would
automatically be created with a
Microsoft managed encryption key so if
you want your customer managed
encryption key to apply on your newly
copied or restored environment you'd
have to link that environment to a
different Power Platform environment and
then apply the Enterprise policy to your
Power Platform
environment the export of environments
um creates a backpack file in your own
storage
this backpack file is also not encrypted
with the customer manag
key that's it